Bhavesh Wadhwani

C Block 8/4, Pimpri, Pune, Maharashtra, 411017 * (+91) 899 911-6241 * bhaveshwadhwani14@gmail.com

Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Results-oriented **Data Scientist** with **2.5+ years** of experience and a proven knowledge of **Computer Vision**, Natural Language Processing (**NLP**), **Machine-learning**, **Deep Learning**, processing real time data. I aim to utilize my skills to successfully fill the **Data Scientist** role at your company.

CAREER SUMMARY

 I am an ML/AI enthusiast with 2+ years experience in Machine Learning, Deep Learning projects, Computer Vision, NLP.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NIHILENT, Pune, Maharashtra

Software Engineer, Nov 2019 -Present

- Client Domain: Banking/ Finance.
- My work here involves **Data Cleaning**, **Data Analysis**, **Data Transformation**, **Labeling Data**, **Development and Deployment of models** for various machine learning tasks.
- $\bullet \quad Training \ / \ tuning \ of \ models \ and \ build \ strategies \ to \ get \ best \ possible \ output \ for \ ML/DL \ task.$
- Achieved 95% accuracy on model for multi-class classification problem on un-structured text data.
- Skills used: Python, NLTK, Azure ML, NLP, Deep Learning, Machine Learning.

INFOSYS, Pune, Maharashtra

Systems Engineer, Dec 2017 - Jun 2019

- Client Domain: ONGC (One of top 10 companies in Fortune 500)
- Certified from Infosys for Python, SQL, Machine Learning, Deep Learning.
- As part of **Infosys NIA OPS-Analytics** team we targeted to improve performance and create high business value and we successfully reduced manual work to 60% by atomizing solutions.
- Cleaned and Analyzed text data using Python, NLP techniques, ML Algorithms.
- We improved performance of servers by 8% and reduce critical alerts by 10% by using previous
 event alert log data using Machine Learning.

EVENTBEEP ENTERTAINMENT LLP, Pune, Maharashtra

Web Developer, Jun 2017 - Dec 2017

About Product: Ticketing platform for college and universities.

- Worked as Full stack developer using technologies like Php, codeignitor framework, javascript, html, css, bootstrap.
- I was **Leading a group** of 5 developers interns.
- Notable work I had contributed in product were Integrating payment gateways to website, SMS and Email integration for ticketing platform, built dynamic display for events .Website link: https://eventbeep.com/.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python.
- Tools: Jupyter Notebook, Github, Image Analysis tools, Microsoft Office.
- Databases: MS-SQL, MySQL, SQLite, Mongo DB.
- Libraries: Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, OpenCV, Dask, Matplotlib, Scipy.
- Frameworks: Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch, Azure ML.
- Machine Learning Algorithms: Linear Regression, KNN, Naive Bayes, Logistic Regression, SGD, SVM, Decision Tree, Random Forest, GBDT, XGBoost, SVD, PCA, K-Means Clustering, MLP, CNN, RNN, LSTM.

PROJECTS

TAXI DEMAND PREDICTION (GitHub)

- Problem Type: Time-Series Data, Regression.
- Models Used: K-Means, Random Forest, XGBoost.
- Problem Statement: Predict number of Taxi required for a given location and for a given time. Detailed <u>Write up Link</u>.

SELF DRIVING CAR BEHAVIORAL CLONING (GitHub)

- **Problem Type**: Computer-Vision, Deep Learning.
- Pipeline Steps Followed:
 - Used the simulator to collect data of good driving behaviour from human input.
 - Designed, trained and validated a model that predicts a steering angle from image data.
 - Used the model to drive the vehicle autonomously around the first track in the simulator. The vehicle should remain on the road for an entire loop around the track.
 - Summarized the results with a written report.
 - Used 3 dashboard camera's captured images per frame at 30 fps to generate video output.
- Problem Statement: Cloning Human behavior for self-driving car on simulator track. End to End driving
 model. Detailed description in this <u>link</u>. Final output video is captured using simulator. Link: <u>Output Video</u>.

COURSES AND CERTIFICATES

- Python, MSSQL-DBA and RDBMS, Certification Exam Infosys Secured 90%
- · Certified on Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Infosys
- Deep Learning Specialization from deeplearning.ai by Andrew Ng @ Coursera
- Data Scientist Track @ Data Camp
- Machine Learning and Deep Learning course at <u>AppliedAl Course</u>.
- Self Driving Car Nanodegree at <u>UDACITY</u>.

EDUCATION

MIT COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING

Pune, Maharashtra

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) Information Technology (Jun 2013-Jun 2017)

• Relevant Coursework: Algorithms, Data Structures, Operating Systems, Systems Programming, Machine Learning, Internet of Things. In Third and fourth year completed 2 Major and 2 minor projects on Machine Learning, Web Development.

JAI HIND HIGH SCHOOL AND JUNIOR COLLEGE

Pune, Maharashtra

High School Diploma (May 2013)

- Relevant Coursework: Science, Math
- Awards & Honors: Science Fair Finalist